DAVID HEALY

drtjprdave@gmail.com | 954-461-1684 | Denver, CO 80219

Summary	7
---------	---

Natural leader offering 11 years of success in managerial positions Looking for a career change in the web development world. Proven skills in aligning operations with market conditions and customer demands to catapult sales forward and strengthen long-term business success. Attentive to company strengths and requirements, effectively balancing goals and resources to achieve consistant results.

Skills -

- Javascript Libraries and Frameworks Problem-Solving
- Website Analytics Tools Deal Closing
- Mobile Application Development
- Process Improvement Web Analytics Tools
- Complex Problem Solving
- Back-End and Database Skills
- Design Software: Sketch, Invision, Photoshop
- Front-End Programming: HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Agile Software Development
- Avid Learner

- Time Management and Prioritization
- User Experience Design
- Project Management
- Negotiation and Persuasion
- Budget Management
- Team Building
- Decision Making
- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB
- Troubleshooting and Testing
- Graphic and User Interface Design

Experience

Regional Sales Manager | Dazbog Coffee Company | 09/2021 - 07/2022

- Managed a territory North of I-70 into Wyoming
- Created/managed a spreadsheet database for myself and other sales reps
- To track new leads and managed account (due to lack of CRM)
- Created/managed Google "MyMaps" tools for tracking leads and existing accounts
- Coordinated trainings and roasting tours
- 60% on the street 40% in office
- Communicated product inconsistencies
- Lead audits tracking inconsistencies in grocery bulk displays

Operations Manager | Blue Tiger USA/ Daiohs/ First Choice Coffee Service | 03/2019 - 09/2021

- Managed a team of a driver and sales professional to lead new sales in high end office coffee in a new territory for Daiohs
- Reported to regional manager and regional sales manager
- P&L
- Payroll
- New employee onboarding
- Created educational PowerPoints on company processes and implemented them

Operations Manager | Black Rock Beverage | 10/2017 - 03/2019

- Started in the red and made company profitable in 3 months
- Reviewed accounts and made appropriate adjustments to client base
- Worked all aspects of the business from deliveries and service to inventory management

• Conducted merger with First Choice Coffee service

On/Off Premise Sales Representative | Cavalier Distribution - Florida | 05/2016 - 10/2017

- 64% YTD/YOY; Current projected sales for 2017: \$603,000.00
- Started with 51 accounts, currently serving 125
- Face to face and phone sales
- Weekly recaps
- Route management though Encompass
- Event management
- Sales strategy and goal setting

General/Front of house Manager, Kitchen Manager | Sybarite Pig, Restaurant | 11/2014 - 03/2016

- Modify existing databases and database management systems
- Inventory maintenance and ordering
- Scheduling
- Staff Training and Continued learning programs

Accounts Manager/Teacher/Other Assorted Titles | Nobel Learning Community | 03/2007 - 03/2011

- Billing for two of the preschools in the area
- AR For the same two schools
- Regional Trainer of accounting software (NetSuite)
- Taught two years of Computer Life Skills courses at Paladin Academy
- Bus driver, after care counselor, Red Cross certified lifeguard

Education and Training

University of Denver | Denver, CO | 10/2022

DU Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Computer Science

References

References Tammy Mays (Nobel Learning Communities) 954-501-1086 Marc Cheever (Cavalier Dist.) 954-298-2727 Brett Mercurio (Krombacher North America) 561-441-9543 Kris Morita (Republic National Dist. Co.) 918-519-5808 Ben Gusmus (First Choice Coffee) 720-237-5121 Brian Savoie (First Choice Coffee Regional Manager) 303-500-9650 Marci Brown (Co-Worker) 720-277-6767

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles -

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-healy-931583130/
- https://github.com/dhealy83
- davidhealy.info